+91 9004855192

Aditi Sharma

rma/ 11 years of experience in Medical Device Industry

aditisharma.7010@gmail.com aditisharma.2011@yahoo.com

linkedin.com/in/aditipsharma/

SUMMARY

The sales and product marketing professional with 11 years of experience, primarily in Medical Devices B2B Business - product management, brand-market development, communication strategy, KOL development-management, product launch-promotions strategy, business development, vendor management and cross-functional stakeholder management. product marketing strategy for target audiences – Radiology, Obs/Gyn, Cardiology, POC-Critical care, Emergency medicine, Anaesthesia and Veterinary markets.

EDUCATION

Indian Institute of Management, Indore	April 2022
Master in Business Administration – General Management	
Dr. D Y Patil University, Mumbai	May 2011
Bachelor of Technology in Biomedical Engineering Grade: First Class with Distinction	

CERTIFICATIONS

Nanyang Business School, Singapore Leadership Program	2022
Successfully completed Strategy Management business simulation	2021
HubSpot Marketing Software certification	2021
Google Analytics certification – by Google	2021
Digital Marketing certification – by Google	2021
Harvard Financial Accounting course certification	2019
• Completed Ultrasound training at Mindray Headquarters in Shenzhen, China	2012
• Completed training related to servicing & maintenance of hospital equipment at Pamtrons, Mumbai	2009

EXPERIENCE

Blue Star Engineering & Electronics

Mumbai, India

Product Manager (India) -CT/MRI/Mammography

07/2022 - 28/06/2024

- Design and implement product marketing plan including new product launches, segmentation targeting positioning, market mapping Radiology, Orthopedic, Neurology
- · Business development strategy for sales & service
- · Management of Marketing Budget, Branding and Promotions.
- · Develop and maintain key stakeholder relationships with regional and leadership teams
- · Collaborate with sales and service to drive Market Development, KOL, KAM activities
- · Develop strong relationships with KOLs across the country
- Actively participate in advisory board meetings related to diagnostic imaging and incorporate KOL input into strategic plans
- · Lead key congresses, events, associations, symposiums interact with and influence the top clinical leaders in Radiology/Imaging industry
- · Meticulously conduct market research to analyse competitive activity

Fujifilm Sonosite India Pvt. Ltd.

Mumbai, India

Clinical Application Specialist – Ultrasound/Echocardiology/Sonography

03/2016 - 10/2020

- · Key Opinion Leaders (KOL) management and customer relationship management
- Sonosite products and its features/software promotions on various platforms virtual & physical as for Product Product Marketing and Brand Management/awareness for cardiology, radiology point of care (critical care, emergency medicine and anaesthesiology), neonatology and veterinary markets
- · Product positioning and messaging/communications that resonates with the target audience
- Product Branding/Promotions through product presentations and features/software marketing in trade shows, Continuing Medical Education (CME) (workshops), and conferences and other promotional campaigns
- · New product promotional activities/product launch/product awareness for New Product Introduction (NPI) in regional/national for targeted audiences as Business strategy
- · Voice of Customer analytics (VOC) for the different target audiences for features/software and product for product development/product marketing.
- Product training, competition knowledge and technical/clinical guidance to sales/service and dealers team
- · New-Market Development Strategy- Neonatology, Pain/MSK, Nephrology for Business Development

+91 9004855192

Aditi Sharma

linkedin.com/in/aditipsharma/

11 years of experience in Medical Device Industry

aditisharma.7010@gmail.com aditisharma.2011@yahoo.com

- · Represented company during tender pre-bids/demonstrations/meetings and preparation of technical documentation and evaluation of government tenders.
- · competitor's product strategy in regions– Competition Analysis and Analytical skills
- · Provided clinical training and on/off-site assistance to doctors and sales/dealer teams

Samsung India Electronics Ltd.

Mumbai, India

02/2015 - 02/2016

- Application Specialist Ultrasound
 - · Pre/post-sale demonstrations of ultrasound systems (radiology, obstetrics/gynecology, cardiology) in the west and the east regions
 - · Product training to sales and dealers team
 - · Product promotions & branding in trade shows, workshops and conferences
 - · Representing company in government tenders, managing key accounts & corporate hospitals.

Mindray Medical India Pvt. Ltd.

Mumbai, India

10/2011 - 01/2015

Application Specialist

- · Brand/Market Development for radiology, obstetrics/gynecology, cardiology, and veterinary for pan India
- · Conducting CME for product-brand promotions, managing trade shows and conference participations
- · Beta testing for new products
- · Developing and managing new/old vendors/dealers
- · Business Development strategy
- KOLs Development & Management across Pan-India and provided on/off-site assistance to doctors and dealer teams
- · Generated reference sites for demonstrations
- · Product training to sales and dealers team
- · Represented company during tender pre-bids/demonstrations/meetings
- · Pre/post-sale demonstrations of ultrasound systems

Siemens India Ltd. - Healthcare

Mumbai, India

Intern in Medical Imaging Department

01/2011 - 06/2011

· Assisted service engineers, application specialists, & sales team in medical imaging modality of computed tomography (CT), magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), Cath Lab, and X-rays

HONOR

•	Was selected for "Emerging Manager Program" mid-senior L&D by Blue Star Management Delivered a lecture as an external faculty from Fujifilm Sonosite for CME on topic, " <i>Ultrasound Guided Regional Anaesthesia Techniques</i> ", organized by Dept. of Anaesthesiology at Government Medial College & Hospital, Nagpur	2023 2020
•	Invited as guest speaker representing Fujifilm Sonosite to impart insights to delegates regarding, "In Vivo Preclinical Imaging and Drug Discovery" in workshop organized by TATA Memorial Centre – Advanced Centre for Treatment, Research and Education in Cancer (ACTREC), , Navi Mumbai	2019
	Part of Asia Pacific Product Development team for Mindray Ultrasound	2013
•	Recognized for excellent contribution to the team in Ultrasound Imaging Systems- Mindray	2013
•	Selected to conduct obstetrics/gynaecology workshop & market development for srilanka – Mindray Colombo, Sri Lanka	2013